조이?
Joey.
Oh my God.
오 마이 갓
Okay.
좋아
So uh...
그러면.. 휴..
I guess we should...make it official huh?
공식적으로 해야겠지?
어.. 이봐 레이첼...
Uh... Look Rach...
Hey Ross is here!
야! 로스가 왔구나!
Hey look! It’s my good friend Ross. Hey Ross.
내 좋은 친구 로스야! 안녕 로스
Hey Joey.
안녕 조이
-Hey you.
-안녕
Hey and look he brought flowers.
이것봐, 꽃까지 가지고 왔네
Thanks Ross, but I’m really more of a candy guy.
고마워 로스, 사실 사탕이 더 갖고 싶지만 뭐... 하하
You’re weird today.
오늘 너 좀 이상하다
Listen I uh, wanted to talk to you about something.
너랑 하고 싶은 말이 있어
그래, 사실 나도 너한테 할 말이 있어
Uh yeah, actually I kinda need to talk to you too.
-Uh Joey, can you give us just a minute?
-No.
-조이, 잠시 둘이 있게 해줄래?
-싫어
What?
뭐라고?
Oh, I’m sorry. I meant no.
미안, 내말은.. 싫다구
Hi! Hey look who’s here!
안녕, 누가 오셨나 봐봐
우리 손녀 어딨지? 보여주려고 마술도 연습해 왔는데 말이야
Where’s my granddaughter? I’ve been practicing my magic tricks.
내 귀에서 25센트짜리 동전을 끄내셨어!
He pulled a quarter out of my ear!
Hey, where’s uh, where’s mom?
엄마는 어디계세요?
리디 고모 데릴러 가셨단다
She went to pick up Aunt Liddy.
Oh, Aunt Liddy’s coming? That means we get five dollars each!
오, 리디 고모도 오세요? 그러면 우리 모두 5달러씩 받겠네!
So when do I get to meet Emma and show her this?
어쨌든, 언제 에마를 만날수 있지? 이걸 보여줘야 하는데
Okay. Wow.
와우...
Uh Dad, Emma’s in the nursery. I’ll take you now. If you want,
아빠 에마는 육아실에 있어요, 지금 데려다 드릴께요
but I really want to talk to you.
하지만 너랑 꼭 할 얘기가 있어
알아, 나도 너한테 할 말이 있어
I know, I still need to talk to you.
Oh hey but, before you guys do that I need to talk to you,
잠깐, 너희들 둘이서 얘기하기전에 너랑 얘기 좀 해야겠어
and Ross, I need to talk to you.
그리고 로스, 너랑도 얘기 좀 해야겠어
Oh and I need to talk to you.
오, 그리고 난 너랑 얘기 좀 해야겠어
About what?
왜?
To see if know what these guys are talking about.
얘네들이 무슨 얘기 하는건지 아냐고 물어볼라고
Isn’t she beautiful?
너무 예쁘지 않아?
Look at her,
쟤 좀 봐
my first grandchild.
내 첫 손자(손녀)야
What about Ben?
벤은 어쩌고요?
Well of course Ben, I meant my first granddaughter. Wow.
당연히 벤이 처음이지, 난 첫 손녀 얘기한거야
Have umm, have you thought anymore about you and Rachel?
너랑 레이첼에 관해서 좀 더 생각해 봤어?
응, 사실 너희들이 모두 방에 들어왔을 때 레이첼한테 얘기 하려던 참이었어
Oh well yeah, actually I was going to talk to her when you guys all came in the room.
잘됐다! 흥분되는걸
Yay! It’s so exciting!
Wow, you could’ve done that with us there.
우리 다 있는데서 얘기해도 됐잖아?
말도 안돼
Yeah right.
Oh sure okay, you can touch yourself in front of us but you can’t talk to Rachel.
그래, 우리 앞에서 자위를 하면서 우리 앞에서 레이첼한테 얘기도 못...
뭐... 뭐?
What?!
When have I ever touched myself in front of you guys?
내가 언제 너희들 앞에서 자위를 했다고 그래?
Oh please! Just before when you were asleep in the lounge!
모르는 척 하지마, 아까 라운지에서 자고 있을 때 말이야
That Armenian family was watching you instead of the TV.
그 아르메니아인 가족들이 TV를 안보고 널 보고 있었잖아
Oh, that reminds me.
아, 그래서 생각이 났는데
That Mr. Hasmeje still has my Gameboy.
그 하즈미지스씨한테서 내 게임보이 받아야겠다
-Hey Chandler, can I talk to you for a second?
-Sure.
-야 챈들러, 잠시 얘기 좀 할까?
-그래
Dude I just did something terrible.
야, 나 나쁜 짓을 저질러 버렸어
That was you?! I thought it was Jack
그게 너였냐? 난 장인어른인 줄 알았는데
No! No, that was Jack!
아니, 그건 로스 아버님 맞았어
Rachel thinks I asked her to marry me!
레이첼이 내가 청혼한 줄 알아
뭐라고? 왜 그런 생각을 해?
What?! Why does she think that?
내가 그런 것 처럼 보였거든
Because it kinda looked like I did.
Again, what?!
다시 묻는데.. 뭐라고?
Okay well, I was down on one knee with the ring in my hand..
반지를 손에 들고 무릎을 꿇고 있었는데..
적어도 하루에 한번은 모두 그런 행동을 하곤 하지
As we all are at some point during the day.
내 반지가 아니었어, 로스의 자켓에서 떨어졌단 말이야
It wasn’t my ring! It fell out of Ross’s jacket!
그걸 줏으려고 무릎을 꿇었더니 레이첼이 청혼한 줄 아는거야
And when I knelt down to pick it up Rachel thought I was proposing!
로스가 반지를 가지고 있었다고?
Ross had a ring?!
And he was gonna propose?
로스가 청혼을 할 작정이었다고?
I guess.
그런가 보지
그런데 니가 선수쳐버렸다고?
And you did it first?!
This is gonna kill him! You know how much he loves to propose!
로스가 화낼꺼야! 걔가 얼마나 청혼하는걸 좋아하는데
알아 나도 안다구, 엉망이야
I know! I know it’s awful.
레이첼이 뭐래?
Well, what did she say?
She said yes.
받아들였어
Does Ross know?
로스가 이 사실을 알아?
Oh God, what the hell am I going to tell him?
오 마이 갓.. 로스한테는 뭐라고 말하지?
Well maybe you don’t have to tell him anything.
아무 말 안해도 될 수도 있어
오 좋은 생각이야, 계속 해봐
Oh, I like that. Yeah...
니가 레이첼한테 다 얘기하면 로스는 이 일에 대해서 알 필요가 없잖아
If you clear things up with Rachel then Ross never needs to find out,
but you have to do it now before he hears about it and kicks your ass!
하지만 빨리 해야돼, 로스가 듣고 널 패버리기 전에 말이야
Now let’s not get carried away.
그건 조금 말이 안되지?
I want a baby.
나 아기 가지고 싶어
여보 내가 얘기했잖아, 내가 반대방향을 보고 있어야 한다고
Honey, we’ve been over this. I need to be facing the other way.
Come on! Come on, if we have sex again it’ll double our chances of getting pregnant.
제발, 우리가 또 섹스를 하면 내가 임신할 확률은 2배가 된다고
아직도 그 방이 비어 있을까?
Do you think that closet’s still available?
I’m so tired.
난 너무 지쳤어
Yeah okay, but no foreplay.
알았어, 하지만 전희는 없는거다
좋지
Deal!
Dad seriously!
아빠, 진짜로요!
그런건 병원에 가봐야 돼요
Y’know you really should see someone about that!
Noted.
고려해 보마
잠시 레이첼이랑 얘기 좀 하고 올께요, 혼자서 괜찮겠어요?
I wanna go talk to Rachel for a minute, are you gonna be okay alone for a bit?
장난하니? 난 여기 서서 영원히 우리 손녀만 바라보고 있어도 괜찮아
Are you kidding me, I could stay and look at her forever.
사실...
Actually umm...
안녕 괜찮아?
Hey! Hi. Are you all right?
Uhh...
음.. 어..
I think I just got engaged.
내가 방금 약혼한 것 같아
오 마이 갓! 걔가 했단 말이야?
Oh my God! He did it?
Well...did you know he was gonna ask me?
걔가 청혼할껄 알고 있었단 말이야?
Are you kidding? I’m like the one who talked him into it.
장난해? 내가 청혼 하라고 설득시켰는걸
내가 우리 그룹의 인형 조종사나 다름없지
I like to think of myself as the puppet master of the group.
And you really think this is a good idea?
이게 진짜 좋은 생각인것 같아?
I just talked him into it, don’t tell me I have to do you too.
내가 방금 걔를 설득 시켰는데, 너까지 설득해야해?
인형 조종사도 지친단 말이야
The puppet master gets tired people.
I just don’t know! It just doesn’t feel right.
모르겠어, 잘못된것 같이 느껴진단 말이야
왜? 너희들은 천생연분이야, 모두들 그렇게 생각하잖아
Why?! You two are so meant to be together, everybody thinks so.
Really?! Even Ross?
진짜? 로스도 그렇게 생각한단 말이야?
Especially Ross!
특히 로스가 그렇게 생각하지
Oh uh, hey Pheebs.
오, 안녕 피비
Uh y’know what? I’ll-I’ll come back later.
있잖아, 내가 나중에 다시 올께
Wow! Kind of uh, kind of a full house here.
와, 여기 다 모여있네
I’ll guess just...I’ll come back.
조금 있다가 다시 오지 뭐
There he goes, your fiancee!
저기 가는구나, 니 약혼자!
I guess so.
그렇게 됐네
잠자면서 자위를 하긴 하지만 말이야
Although he does play with himself in his sleep.
I can’t say that I’m surprised.
전혀 놀랍지 않아
아빠 뭐하세요?
Dad, what are you doing?
I think there are people in there having sex.
저 안에서 사람들이 섹스 하고 있는 것 같아
It can’t be me, I’m standing right here.
나일리는 없어, 난 여기 서있잖아
Wanna peek?
훔쳐볼래?
-싫어요
-뭐가 어때?
-No!
-Come on!
Y’know what? I don’t like you without mom.
있잖아요, 아빠는 엄마가 없으면 이상해요
Come on.
가자
We’re not peeking?
훔쳐보기는 안하고?
Well I’m peeking.
난 훔쳐봐야지
Oh my God!
오 마이 갓!
Hello sir, you know Monica.
안녕하세요 장인어른, 모니카 아시죠?
Hey uh, is it okay to come in?
안녕, 들어가도 돼?
물론이지
Of course! Oh Joey,
오 조이, 이 반지는..
this ring
I...it’s beautiful I love it!
너무 아름다워, 마음에 들어
Yeah uh look Rach,
그래.. 이봐, 레이첼 사실..
there’s something I gotta tell ya.
너한테 할 말이 있어
안녕하세요, 다시 젖먹이기에 시도해 볼래요?
Hey! Hey! Are you ready to try nursing again?
그럼요, 안녕 에마
Yeah! Hi Emma.
Hey, why do you think she won’t take my breast?
왜 내 가슴을 안받아 줄까요?
괜찮아요, 원래 아기들이 받아들이는데 시간이 좀 걸려요
It’s all right honey, it takes some babies a while to get it,
하지만 걱정마요, 될꺼니까
but don’t worry. It’ll happen.
아이구
Yowsa!
괜찮아 얘야, 넌 할 수 있어
Okay sweetie, you can do it.
Just open up and put it in your mouth.
입을 열고 입안에 집어넣으면 되는거야
오 마이 갓
Dear Lord.
I’m sorry honey, what were you saying?
미안, 아까 뭐라고 하고 있었지?
Oh uh-uh yeah, I think that...
맞아, 그래... 어.. 내 생각엔..
Oh look, she’s pulling away again!
오 이것 봐요, 또 입을 떼잖아요
Do you think my nipples are too big for her mouth?
얘 입에 넣기에 제 젖꼭지가 너무 큰걸까요?
She looks scared. Doesn’t she look scared?
무서워 보여요, 무서워 보이지 않아?
Y’know, I don’t really know her.
내가 잘 모르는 애라서 말이지..
가슴을 마사지 해보는건 어때요? 모유의 흐름이 더욱 활발해지도록 말이에요
Why don’t we try massaging the breast to stimulate the flow.
지금 장난하는 거에요?
Are you kidding me?!
It’s just so frustrating! Why doesn’t she want my breast?!
참 이상하네, 왜 내 젖을 원치 않는거지?
I don’t know! Maybe she’s crazy!
몰라! 쟤가 미쳐서 그런 걸 수도 있지!
Oh hey! Wait up!
오, 기다려봐
Hi!
안녕
Congratulations!
축하해!
조이가 알고 있는지 몰라서 걔 앞에서는 얘기 안했어
I didn’t want to say anything in front of Joey ‘cause I didn’t know if he knew yet.
What, that we had a baby?
뭐, 아기가 태어났다는걸?
Come on let’s give him a little credit,
조이라도 인정해 줄껀 인정해 줘야지
although, he did eat a piece of plastic fruit earlier.
아까 플라스틱 과일을 먹긴 했지만 말이야
No! No, that you and Rachel are engaged!
아니, 너랑 레이첼이 약혼했다는거 말이야
뭐?
What?
Oh, it’s a secret.
오, 원래 비밀인거니?
Oh goodie! Yes! We haven’t done the secret thing in a long time.
좋았어! 재미있겠다! 비밀같은거 오래간만이잖아
Phoebe, there is no secret.
피비, 비밀같은건 없어
알겠어? 난 청혼한 적 없다고
Okay? I didn’t propose.
Are you lying?
지금 거짓말하는거야?
저번에 니가 닥터(의사)라고 우기던 때 처럼 말이야?
Is this like that time you tried to convince us that you were a doctor?
I am a doctor!
나 닥터(박사) 맞아!
있잖아, 내가 그냥 가서 레이첼이랑 직접 얘기 좀 해야겠어
Y’know what? I’m just gonna go and talk to Rachel myself.
All right, me too.
좋아, 나도 갈래
-Should we wake her up?
-No! No,
-깨울까?
-아니
자게 놔둬, 피곤하잖아
come on let her sleep! She’s so exhausted.
And so engaged.
확실히 약혼 맞잖아, 짠짠짠~!
오 마이 갓!
What? Oh my God!
우리가 약혼한 줄 아나봐!
She-she thinks we’re engaged!
왜? 왜 우리가 약혼했다고 생각하는거지?
Why? Why? Why would she think we’re engaged?!
Perhaps because you gave her an engagement ring?
니가 약혼반지를 줘서 그런건 아닐까?
있잖아 로스, 의사는 원래 똑똑한거야
Y’know Ross doctors are supposed to be smart.
저 반지를 준 적이 없다고
I didn’t give her that ring!
안줬다고?
Really?
안줬어!
No!
그럼 누구 반지야?
So whose ring is it?
It’s mine.
내꺼야
약혼반지야?
Is it an engagement ring?
응
Yes!
But you didn’t give it to her?
그런데 니가 준건 아니라고?
No!
그래
But you were going to propose?
청혼 할려고 했던거야?
아니야
No!!
Huh, I might be losing interest in this.
흠.. 이젠 이게 재미가 없어졌어
Look. Look, my mom gave me that ring
이봐, 엄마가 나한테 저 반지를 준거야
because she wanted me to propose to Rachel,
레이첼한테 청혼하라면서 말이야
하지만 내가 하고 싶었던건.. 그냥..
but all I wanted to do is if she maybe...
kinda...wanted ah...start...things up again.
다시 둘 사이를 시작하는게 어떨지 묻고 싶은것 뿐이었다고
Oh, what beautiful lukewarm sentiment.
너무나 아름답고 재미없는 말인걸
Look, I didn’t want to rush into anything. And it seemed like she didn’t want to either.
너무 빨리 나아가고 싶지 않았어, 레이첼도 같은 생각인것 같고 말이야
하지만 이 모든게 어떻게 된 일인지는 이해가 안가
But I don’t, I don’t understand how any of this happened!
What? Did she find the ring in my jacket,
레이첼이 내 자켓에서 반지를 찾아서
assume that I was going to propose,
내가 청혼할꺼라고 생각해서 반지를 끼고
throw it on, and-and just start telling people?
사람들한테 얘기했단 말이야?
No! No, she said you actually proposed to her.
아니야, 레이첼이 니가 확실히 청혼했다고 했어
Well I didn’t!
난 한 적 없다니까
I didn’t propose!
청혼 한 적 없다고!
Unless uh...
만약..
했나?
Did I?
I haven’t slept in forty hours and..
40시간째 잠 한숨도 못잤고..
it does sound like something I would do...
내가 할 만한 짓이긴 한데...
Look, we can’t stay in here forever.
여기서 영원히 있을 수는 없잖아
Oh, I still can’t believe my dad saw us having sex!
아빠가 우리가 섹스하는걸 봤다니 믿기지 않아
He didn’t make it to one of piano recitals, but this he sees!
내 피아노 독주회는 한번도 못왔으면서 이건 보다니
괜찮아, 우린 다 어른이잖아
This is okay. We’re all adults here;
there’s nothing to be ashamed of.
부끄러워 할 필요는 없어
Now, let’s put our underwear in our pockets and walk out the door.
어서 우리 속옷을 주머니에 넣고 나가자
뭐해요 아빠?
Hi Dad!
아빠라고 불러도 되는거죠?
I can still call you that right?
Of course. I’ll always be your dad.
물론이지, 난 언제나 너의 아빠니까
I just want you to know that what you witnessed in there,
이것만을 아셨으면 해요, 장인어른께서 방금...
목격하신건... 재미를 위해서 한게 아니에요
that wasn’t for fun.
It wasn’t fun?!
재미가 없었다고?
Why? Why-why-would you?Wh-why...?
왜? 왜 갑자기..?
Look, I just don’t want you to think that
그냥 우리가 하고 싶을 때 언제나 하는
we’re animals who do it whenever we want.
그런 동물들로 보시진 말아 주세요
Oh, I don’t think that.
그렇게 생각하는건 아니다
Before today I never thought of you two having sex at all.
오늘 전까지는 너희들이 전혀 섹스를 안하고 산다고 생각했었지
It was a simpler time.
모든게 간단한 시대였지
The truth is, Dad, we’re-we’re trying.
사실은.. 아빠, 아기를 가져보려는 거에요
What?
뭐라고?
Yeah, we’re trying to get pregnant.
임신을 하려고 노력중이라고요
Oh my God! This is so exciting!
오 마이 갓, 너무나 흥분되는걸
Well, get back in there! I’ll guard the door!
어서 다시 들어가, 내가 문을 지키고 있을테니까!
Well, that’s okay dad, we-we can wait until later.
괜찮아요, 나중에 하죠 뭐
Whoa-whoa-whoa! I don’t think so! Aren’t you ovulating?
그러면 안돼지, 지금 배란중이지 않니?
Daddy?!
아빠!
Well you gotta get at it princess!
그러면 얼른 해야 돼, 얘야
너희 엄마와 내가 널 낳으려고 할 때는 말이지
When your mother and I were trying to conceive you,
whenever she was ovulating, bam, we did it.
너희 엄마 배란중일 때마다 해버렸단다
That’s how I got my bad hip.
그게 내 허리가 안좋아진 이유지
우연이네요, 이 대화가 내 머리에 총알이 박힌 이유거든요
That’s funny, this conversation’s how I got the bullet hole in my head.
한번은 내가 무릎을 싱크대에 이렇게 올리고, 너희 엄마는...
This one time I had my knee up on the sink and your mother, she was...
아빠! 엄마랑 아빠랑 섹스할때 사용한 체위에 관해선 얘기하지 않아도 될것 같아요
Daddy! I don’t think we need to hear about the specific positions you and mom had sex.
그래 맞아, 너희들의 체위가 중요한거지
You’re right, you’re right. This is about your positions.
내가 저안에서 봤던 그 체위는 임신하기에 최적의 체위가 아니야
Now, what I saw in the closet is not the optimum position for conceiving a child,
although it might feel good.
기분은 좋더라도 말이야
I don’t feel good right now.
지금 기분은 그리 좋지 않은데요
But pleasure is important, and it helps if the woman has an orgasm.
쾌감은 중요해, 그리고 여자가 오르가즘을 느끼면 더욱 좋지
자신있나? 사위?
You up to the task sailor?
장인어른, 진짜 제 뇌가 벽에 다 튀어 버리겠어요
Seriously sir, my brains? All over the wall.
-Hey.
-안녕
오, 너한테 해줄 말이 있어
I need to tell you something.
Well, now’s a good time.
지금 해두는게 좋을꺼야
지금 내 귀를 잘라버리러 가는 길이었거든
I’m on my way to have my ears cut off.
Joey asked me marry him.
조이가 결혼하자고 했어
뭐?
What?
조이가 청혼했다고
Joey proposed to me.
걔 미쳤니? 방금 로스의 아기를 낳았잖아
Is he crazy?! You just had Ross’s baby!
근데.. 내가 좋다고 했어
Well, I-I said yes.
너 미쳤니? 방금 로스의 아기를 낳았잖아
What?! Are you crazy? You just had Ross’s baby!
It’s-it’s so inappropriate.
너무 부적절하잖아
No, it’s worse than that. It’s wrong. It’s...
그것보다 잘못된거야, 그, 그건...
It is bigger than mine!
내꺼보다 크잖아!
I know. Days of Our Lives, thank you very much.
당연하지, 드라마 주연 배우잖아
You can’t marry him!
조이랑 결혼하면 안돼
왜 안돼?
Why not?
이 모든걸 혼자서 하고 싶지 않아, 그리고 조이는 너무나 착하잖아
I don’t want to do this alone! And he’s such a sweet guy
그리고 나를 얼마나 사랑한다고
and he loves me so much.
Well do you love him?
너도 조이를 사랑해?
Sure.
그래
'그래'라고?
Sure?
Yeah, I mean whatever.
그래.. 그런거 비슷한거지 뭐
레이첼, 중요한건...
Honey, the question is...
do you really want to marry Joey?
진짜로 조이랑 결혼하고 싶어?
No.
아니
아니야
No, I don’t.
니가 가서 조이한테 얘기해줄래?
Could you be a dear and go tell him?
You still haven’t told Rachel you weren’t really proposing?
레이첼한테 아직도 진짜로 청혼한게 아니라고 말을 안했단 말이야?
No! She had the ring on, she seemed so excited,
못했어, 반지를 끼고 너무나 좋아하더라고
and then she took her breast out.
그러더니 가슴을 꺼내보이더라고!
조이 사실을 얘기해야해! 그리고 가슴은 어떻게 생겼던?
Joey, you have to tell her what’s going on! And what did it look like?!
I didn’t look at it.
안봤어
Stupid baby’s head was blocking most of it.
.. 아기의 머리가 가려버리지 뭐야
Go and tell Rachel right now before Ross finds out.
어서 가서 레이첼한테 얘기해, 로스가 알기 전에
Look, it’s not that easy.
그렇게 쉬운게 아니야
나랑 결혼하고 싶다고 했단 말이야, 상처를 주고 싶진 않아
She said she wanted to marry me. I don’t want to hurt her.
그냥.. 부드럽게 얘기해
Okay, look, just do it gently.
그래, 니말이 맞아
You’re right. You’re right.
I-I’ll go tell her now before Ross finds out and I’ll be gentle.
로스가 알기 전에 지금 가서 얘기할께, 부드럽게 말이야
I can do that. I am a gentle person.
물론이지, 난 부드러운 남자니까
Oh, by the way. Two people screwing in there if you want to check that out.
아 참, 저 안에 두사람이 섹스하고 있으니까 보고 싶으면 봐
Hey.
안녕
Listen, I um...
있잖아, 나...
I heard about the engagement.
청혼 얘기는 들었어
놀랐어?
Surprised?
놀라고 당황했다고 할 수 있지
And confused.
Rach, sweetie, I-I um...
레이첼, 나.. 난 말이야...
난 너한테 청혼 하지 않았어
I didn’t propose to you.
I know.
알아
I don’t think you do.
잘 모르는거 같은데
You didn’t propose to me.
넌 나한테 청혼 한 적 없어
조이가 청혼했지
Joey did.
불쌍한 레이첼, 많이 지쳤구나
Poor baby, you’re so tired.
레이첼..
Rach,
난 너한테 청혼 하지 않았고..
I didn’t propose to you,
조이도 너한테 청혼 하지 않았고..
Joey didn’t propose to you
and Chandler didn’t propose to you.
그리고 챈들러도 너한테 청혼 하지 않았어
Uh... You didn’t propose to me,
넌 나한테 청혼 하지 않았고..
챈들러는 물론 나한테 청혼 하지 않았지
Chandler didn’t propose to me,
하지만 조이는 했어
but Joey did.
조이가 너한테 청혼을 했다고?
Joey proposed to you?
나중에 올께
I can come back.
잠깐, 잠깐만 조이..
Hey, wait! Wait-wait-wait!
Joey, did you propose to her?
레이첼한테 청혼했어?
No.
아니
Yes you did!
했잖아
사실, 원칙적으로는... 안했어
Actually, technically, I didn’t.
Well then why did you give me a ring?
그러면 왜 반지를 준거야?
잠깐, 니가..
Wait! Whoa-whoa, you..
you gave her the ring?
니가 레이첼한테 반지를 줬다고?
아니야, 그리고 레이첼한테 결혼해달라고 말하지도 않았어
No! No, and I did not ask her to marry me!
했잖아
Yes, you did!
No, I didn’t!
안했어
했어
Yes, you did!
안했어
No, I didn’t!
했어, 그리고 안했단 말은 하지마!
Yes, you did! And don’t you say, "No, I didn’t!"
조이가 바로 저기에서 무릎을 꿇고 청혼을 했다고
He was right there. He got down on one knee and proposed.
잠깐, 무릎까지 꿇었다고?
Whoa! You were down on one knee?
그래 오해 할만 하지, 하지만 절대!
Yeah. Yeah, that looks bad. But I didn’t...
I didn’t propose!
청혼하지는 않았어!
그럼 무슨일이 일어났던 거야?
Then what did happen?
Yeah, what did happen?
그래, 무슨일이 일어난거야?
좋아, 반지가 바닥에 떨어져서 줏으려고 무릎을 굽혔는데
Okay, the ring fell on the floor and I went down to pick it up
and you thought I was proposing.
니가 내가 청혼한다고 '생각'한거지
Yeah, but you said, "Will you marry me?"
하지만 니가 '나와 결혼해줘'라고 얘기까지 했잖아
안했어
No, I didn’t!
했어
Yes, you did!
안했어
No, I didn’t!
Yes, you did?Oh my God you didn’t!
했어.. 오 마이 갓, 안했구나!
그러면 왜 더 일찍 얘기하지 않은거야?
Well then why didn’t you tell me that before?!
Well I tried, but people kept coming in
그러려고 했지, 하지만 사람들이 자꾸 들이닥치고
and then you took your breast out!
니가 가슴을 꺼내보여서...
잠깐만!
Whoa! Hey! Whoa-whoa-whoa,
레이첼의 가슴을 봤다고?
you saw her breast?!
I’ll tell you about it later. Be cool.
나중에 얘기해줄께, 흥분하지마
그러면 조이, 왜 약혼반지를 가지고 있었던 거야?
Well then Joey, what the hell were you doing with an engagement ring?!
It wasn’t my ring!
내 반지가 아니었어!
It’s Ross’s ring! That’s why I felt so bad Rach,
로스의 반지란 말이야, 그래서 더욱 미안했던거야
로스가 너한테 청혼할 예정이었단 말이야
because he was going to propose.
뭐라고?
What?!
You were gonna propose to me?
청혼할 작정이었어?
Uhh...
그게...
아니
No.
Well, this is awkward.
이거 분위기 참 어색하군
But I-I was going to see if y’know, maybe you uh,
하지만 니가..
다시 사귈 마음 있는지는 물어 보려고 했지
start dating again
but that?I mean that-that was all, Rach.
하지만.. 그게 다였어
Dude, step up! I proposed.
야 수준 좀 높여라, 난 청혼까지 했잖아
안했어
No, you didn’t!
Oh that’s right. There’s a lot going on here and I think I ate some bad fruit earlier.
아 그렇지, 이것저것 너무 복잡한데다 아까 상한 과일을 먹은 것 같아
Hey, she just woke up!
안녕하세요, 방금 일어났어요
She’s hungry.
배가 고픈가봐요
-다시 한번 시도해보죠
-좋아요
-Why don’t we give this another try?
-Okay.
왜 내가 청혼할 작정이었다고 얘기한거야?
I can’t believe you told her I was going to propose!
왜 청혼을 안한다는거야?
I can’t believe you’re not going to propose!
난 서두르지 않을꺼야
Hey, I’m not going to rush into anything!
Oh yeah, dude, I totally understand.
그래, 완벽히 이해해
나도 보통 아기를 낳고나면 천천히 가려 하지
Usually after I have a baby with a woman I like to slow things down!
-오 마이 갓
-뭐?
-Oh my God!
-What?
먹고 있어, 모유를 먹고 있다고! 봐봐
She’s doing it Look, she’s breast-feeding look!
Ah, it’s beautiful.
너무나 아름다워!
나중에 다시 데리러 올께요
I’ll come back for her later.
-Okay.
-Thank you.
-네
-고마워요
Oh wow, this feels weird.
와, 기분 이상하네
Good weird?
기분 좋게 이상해?
너무나 좋게 이상해
Wonderful weird.
있잖아 얘들아.. 나, 나도 갈께
Y’know what you guys? I’m uh, I’m gonna go too.
And uh, I’m sorry about everything.
그리고, 미안해.. 모두다
조이 걱정마, 내 잘못이잖아
Honey don’t worry, it was my mistake.
No, Rach, I should’ve told you sooner. It’s just that...
아니야 레이첼, 내가 일찍 얘기했어야 하는데..
Man! That kid is going to town!
와! 저 아기 열심인데!
완벽해
She’s perfect.
우린 참 복 받은거야
We’re so lucky.
맞아, 우린 복 받은거야
We really are.
Look, I-I know it’s not a proposal..
이봐, 이게 청혼도 아니고..
and I don’t know where you are,
니가 어떤 상태에 있는지는 모르겠지만..
but with everything that’s been going on and with Emma and..
지금까지 있어왔던 일들과 에마까지..
그런게 느껴져
I’ve been feeling...
I know. I know. I’ve feeling...
알아, 나도 느껴져
-그래?
-응
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Okay, well, that..
좋아.. 와..
Wow, okay, well, umm..
그럼.. 우리..
then maybe, at least we can, we can talk about us again.
적어도 '우리'에 관해서 얘기라도 해볼 수 있겠다
그래..
Yeah, maybe.
Well good, okay. I-I, kind of think y’know if we...if...
잘됐어.. 내, 내 생각에는 우리가 만약...
반지를 끼고 있네..
You’re wearing the ring.
Wh-what’s that?
뭐, 뭐라고?
그리고 피비한테 약혼했다고 말을 했지..
And you told Phoebe you were engaged...
미안, 뭐라고?
I’m sorry, what?
When you thought Joey proposed did...
조이가 청혼했다고 생각했을때...
did you say yes?
좋다고 했던거야?
얘들아 의사선생님이랑 얘기했는데
Kids, I spoke to a doctor
and picked up this pamphlets on how to get pregnant.
임신하는 방법에 관한 팜플렛을 하나 얻어왔다
Hey dad!
안녕하세요 아빠
Sorry to bother you again, but could you pass my pamphlets back?
또 방해해서 죄송한데요, 제 팜플렛 좀 다시 밀어주시겠어요?
Thank you.
고마워요